<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-07T03:03:38-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mark Phillips</title><subtitle>American Americanist</subtitle><entry><title type="html">MEOW Coin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/compuglobalhypermegacorp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MEOW Coin" /><published>2019-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/compuglobalhypermegacorp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/compuglobalhypermegacorp/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/whitepaper001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;white paper&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/compuglobalhypermegacorp&quot;&gt;Mr. Whiskers’ Whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Proof of Meow®&lt;/strong&gt; – provides solutions to classical computer science’s intractable problems including O(k^n), O(2^n), exponential; O(n!), factorial; and O(n^n ), super-exponential in “meow, hiss, purr, meow”.* &lt;a href=&quot;https://etherscan.io/token/0x4ed4DDd7981e347b673f697DC821965A3EB64b9c&quot;&gt;Etherscan.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/whitepaper003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;white paper diagram&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pleasemarkdarkly/simpleblockchain&quot;&gt;Play with Mr. Whisker’s simple blockchain.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WSDOT Collision Predictions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wsdot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WSDOT Collision Predictions" /><published>2019-07-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wsdot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wsdot/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/accidents.png&quot; alt=&quot;accident modeling&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To better understand accidents in the Northwest, I processed the WSDOT’s data on serious to fatal accidents. Specifically, I processed the WSDOT reported collisions and mapped them to the nearest intersections, ranked, color-coded our 500 top dangerous intersections and displayed them on a heatmap by the frequency of accidents by date and time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I requested WSDOT to provide Northwest collisions between 2015 through June 2018 which I parsed grouping by city and date, then used Alteryx to forecast by week accidents after which I use Python to weight each day afterwhich I feed into Tableau for visualization. The result is a map of our area that uses the current day to present locations which have been historically and forecasted to be probable for collisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code and dataset may be accessed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pleasemarkdarkly/wsdot_visualization&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The code consists of three scripts. The first one, “wsdot_parser.py”, will open the WSDOT dataset. Please note that the code assumes that the dataset will be on the same folder level and named “king.csv”. This script will generate two derived datasets: “weekday_coeffs.csv” and “weekly_table.csv”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is a table where the general probability of an accident per city and weekday (Monday-Sunday) is represented by a number (0 to 1). The second one is the aggregate accidents per week over the full dataset grouped by city. Each row represents a week and it just counts the number of accidents that happened on that week at that city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do the actual forecast Alteryx Designed is required. The script provided (“arima_iter.yxmc”) will produce a forecast of accidents for the selected city (you must manually choose it in the Alteryx interface). This forecast is per week and each row represents a week for that city and is the result of an ARIMA model fit to the whole dataset per city and week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all the cities have a forecast then the Python script “merger.py” will produce the final forecast for the next 16 weeks starting on the last date found on the WSDOT dataset. The general forecast for a week is spread between the days of that week, weighting each day by the weekday coefficient previously computed. At the end, the file “full_forecast.csv” is produced as the final output. This file can feed Tableau to create a visualization.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">docker_mac_apt</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mac-apt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="docker_mac_apt" /><published>2019-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mac-apt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mac-apt/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/markedphillips/docker_mac_apt&quot;&gt;MacOSX forensic analysis framework containerized.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mac_apt is a python based framework, which has plugins to process individual artifacts (such as Safari internet history, Network interfaces, Recently used files, Spotlight typed searches..) The framework does the heavy lifting, parsing of disk/volume image and offers a unified output interface, which currently supports writing out data as CSV, Sqlite and Excel formats. There is an API which plugins can use to access files and folders within the disk image. Currently DD and E01 images are supported. DMG files without compression work too. You can use a mounted image too (with limited support on windows for this feature). We even put in a native HFS parser adding support for lzvn/lzfse compressed files.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">MacOSX forensic analysis framework containerized.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Greenplay Format</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/modpod/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Greenplay Format" /><published>2006-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2006-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/modpod</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/modpod/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod.png&quot; alt=&quot;AutoPC&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A self-enclosed, flat-panel device for retailers to offer in-store sampling, purchasing and fulfillment of digital music and movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/greenplay.png&quot; alt=&quot;Greenplay&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studio approved video content purchsae and rental through SD cards and PC peripherals, including $99 video player.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsoft Smart Watch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsoft Smart Watch" /><published>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2005-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spot/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/spot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MSN Direct&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architecture that enables peer-to-peer communication between SPOT devices, specifically SPOT watches. Example channels include Peer to Peer Poker, Chat, and Eightball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dotnetcpu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;.netcpu&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial BASIC Stamp chip developed for educational purposes using portions of Microsoft’s SPOT technology to execute C# code and an embedded TinyCLR (Common Language Runtime).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MP3 Jukebox</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/digital-jukebox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MP3 Jukebox" /><published>2002-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2002-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/digital-jukebox</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/digital-jukebox/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DJ&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy-to-use digital music player that combines the clarity of digital audio with the power and fidelity of home stereo. Enables consumers to play and record music from CDs, tapes, records, or digital file formats (MP3, WMA, and AAC) and to display album, artist, and song title, and to store and browse 1000 CDs, and record albums and tapes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transworld Entertainment Sampling Station</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/twec/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transworld Entertainment Sampling Station" /><published>2002-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2002-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/twec</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/twec/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lvs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hipzip&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-store listening and viewing station that uses Windows Media technology to store and stream content; lets shoppers scan and preview any CD or DVD in retailer’s catalog and enables use cross merchandising, loyalty programs, point-of-sale integration, and chain-wide “try and buy”programs. Deployed in more than 600 stores and 13,000 stations and remains the world’s largest deployment of a listening solution technology.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Iomega Hipzip, Clik! 40MB Drive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Iomega-Hipzip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Iomega Hipzip, Clik! 40MB Drive" /><published>1999-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>1999-09-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Iomega-Hipzip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Iomega-Hipzip/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/iomega.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hipzip&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the firsts multi-codec mp3 players from Interactive Objects aka Fullplay Media Systems. The software stack for the Iomega Hipzip, built upon eCos which was called Dadio OS, source code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pleasemarkdarkly/iomega_hipzip&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  Palm-sized personal digital audio player that uses the Dharma digital media reference platform and combines high capacity removable storage technology with low-cost PocketZip media; supports MP3 and WMA formats, and uses Dadio to support concurrent downloads and play list management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkout the campy manual &lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/hipzip.pdf&quot;&gt;Iomega Hipzip Manual&lt;/a&gt;. Iomega Hipzip Manual&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Digital Stereo Audio Development Platform</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dharma-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Digital Stereo Audio Development Platform" /><published>1999-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>1999-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dharma-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dharma-development/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/dharma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;digital audio platform&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fully developed portable stereo reference platform that provides a turnkey solution for digital audio integration into consumer electronics systems, computer peripherals, portable audio players, or home stereo systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/maverick_chip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;maverick audio platform&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware platform for prototyping digital media appliances that enables the development of a broad range of digital audio products (portable digital audio players, Internet radios, digital audio receivers, digital home jukebox systems, and digital car stereos) using a common interoperable design. Based on Cirrus Logic’s Maverick family of microprocessors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Windows Media Player Casseopia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/windows-media-player/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Windows Media Player Casseopia" /><published>1999-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>1999-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/windows-media-player</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/windows-media-player/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/mediaplayer.png&quot; alt=&quot;Windows Media Player for CE&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows Media Player 5 for Pocket PC that enables the playing of Windows Media and MP3 audio and video files stored on a device or network; first embedded software media player showcasing WMA and the first WMA DRM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>